Hi, if you're like me, you spent hours scrolling on TikTok or Pinterest looking at Minecraft
building ideas without the intent to ever actually build them. Now, I don't know about you, but
sometimes inspiration just randomly hits. And I have to play Minecraft. Like, that's all that's
on my mind. And lately I've been seeing a whole lot of cottagecore Minecraft content circulating
around the internet, getting a lot of views. And so I downloaded some shaders and launched
Minecraft at like 6 FPS and built this for nostalgia. And if you're like literally any
person who's played Minecraft over the years, these houses were the bomb. They were like move-in
ready. Of course, there was only room for like three things to fit in there, and then there was
this problem. It's Minecraft cottagecore aesthetic because the mushroom houses with this aesthetic
are like next level. They are chef's kiss. They are immaculate. And suddenly your wiki how tutorial
and I will be making my first tutorial on how to make simple mushroom houses featuring acacia plank flooring are more anaesthetic than the 2013 mustache trend.
and if this strangely specific scenario applies to you, then, uh, boy will you like this tutorial.
so now I present three ways to make mushroom houses in Minecraft.
YAY!
So the first house is pretty easy.
You're going to want to start out with a statistically impossible mushroom in the middle of a field
and use bone meal to make it big.
Now stare at that mushroom until you decide to mutilate it to look aesthetic, like this.
I wanted the mushroom to look a bit different than the other simple mushroom houses you
typically see, so I went for more of a bell-shaped curve for the top of the mushroom.
You could also use one of those mini water bottles for reference.
I modeled mine based on an upside down flower pot and I think it turned out pretty good.
Once you have achieved maximum upside down flower pot conformity, then you can start
modifying the stem to make it look stalkier.
I used the mushroom stem block and smooth quartz stairs, and if you're in survival you'll
probably want to mine a few of the big mushrooms with a silk touch axe to get the materials
for this.
I used birch plank flooring to match the rest of the interior.
Now I really like this house but there not much room Sorry for my spore sense of humor Here the big grand reveal of this house Very simple I give it a 8 out of 10
Next house! This is a little bit more difficult than the last one, and so you're gonna start out by making a frame that looks like the outline of a handmade cube of playdough.
The kind that the edges never seem sharp enough.
And then start sculpting it to look like the body of this absurdly priced plastic Minnie Mouse teapot I found on Amazon.
Amazon. I use smooth quartz blocks, slabs, and stairs to accomplish this. And if you
want to use mushroom stem blocks, I'm sure you could, but I just like quartz because
it makes the mushroom stems seem smooth and continuous, sort of like a differentiable
equation. Also because it's not a pain to get all those stems. After this, start making
the stem taller to look almost like a BB-8, and then give the wannabe BB-8 some helicopter
blades. These will be the radius of your circular mushroom cap. Then connect those little helicopter
Blades to form a circle. Also, I never really found these graphs useful. I always find them on
like TikTok, but then again, I always just wing it and it doesn't look very circular, so maybe
they're helpful to you, but mine turned out pretty great in the end. Anyway, start outlining the
circle in red mushroom blocks and then be indecisive and then decide on making the easy
way out and make a circular spherical looking mushroom cap. Mine is about six blocks tall and
unlike me you probably want to make sure there's no weird blocks left exposed
then I made the door in the window and outlined them in the most superior wood
type spruce wood I used planks fences and stairs as well as oak leaves for the
window boxes to add some extra whimsy you can make a dilapidated cobblestone
chimney and drape that with oak leaves to add some stuff to the interior I
connected the chimney to a fireplace furnace type thing and then added an
unnecessary amount of bookshelves and leaves because when in doubt to add oak
leaves and bookshelves. That's my motto. Also, I used flower pots, turtle eggs, and sea pickles
for the inside, and then I discovered that in 1.16.5, you can place turtle eggs on flower pots,
which is kind of weird. Anywho, I used vines as a ladder to the attic area, which will be a cute
little bedroom. I outlined the roof with spruce wood and then placed some bookshelves behind them.
This would also be a cool enchanting room but the house demands a bedroom so I added in a skylight which looks good with the shaders and I sure it would look good without them So this is the finished build It only took me about 45 minutes to do in creative so not too bad Ta Right on to the last one This one is kind of hard but not
like prior or gaming at the end of his TikToks kind of hard. You're going to want to start out
with a circular base like such and then add a small circle attached to it. Once you have your
Diffence.
I'm just going to go ahead and start with the circle.
So I'll start with the circle and then I'll do the centerpiece.
I'm going to make sure that the two little circle buddies start making them taller and
rounder.
I focused on the bigger circle first because it's going to be the centerpiece for the build.
Also if this video gets 100 likes I'll make a video of my little sister following this
tutorial to see how she does because she's bad at building and I'm bad at explaining
things.
Okay back to the tutorial.
If you don't know what shape to make the base of the big mushroom I refer to the gourd from
the 2007 Disney classic Secret of the Magic Gourd and mine turned out pretty alright.
Also I need to know was anyone else lowkey traumatized by that movie cause when I first
I guess I just thought gourds were strange pumpkins so for the longest time I was fundamentally confused on what gourds were
So anyway, you're gonna start making another one of those helicopter circle things
and here's a better explanation using calculus if you want to know how to make circles in Minecraft
Presenting! Building circles! Yay!
So you're gonna want to start out with this sort of graph paper, just trace something circular onto it
and then fill in the blocks that the circle crosses
make sure it all has the same radius. And then this is where the calculus comes in. If you look at tangent lines, you know what tangent lines are, I hope. You probably don't. But the slope of the tangent line is sort of the slope of if you were to draw the slope through the grid squares of the circle. This made a lot more sense inside my head. But you can trace pretty much any circle on the graph paper and repeat this process. Just make sure the radius is the same and that each quadrant is the same. And there you go. You have a
Circle in Minecraft.
Okay now moving on to our other little mushroom buddy, you're going to want to make him a
wonky little mushroom that sort of stems off from the big one.
It's really hard to explain how I did this, but I would recommend using organic shapes
and have the top of the mushroom thinner than the base.
Then add a tiny little cap.
For the top of the big mushroom, I basically did the same thing as I did for the medium
tutorial and despite it being vastly bigger the cap is about the same height Maybe even 5 blocks this time I kind of to make it sorta squishy like the first build but I lost all my brain cells thinking about calculus
If you want the mushroom to be super cottagecore, you can add some birch leaves that hang like
vines and some hanging lanterns.
You could also use shroomlights.
I also added an elapidated chimney to match the vibe.
And then for the interior, I started again by connecting the fireplace to the chimney
and built a loft area with a ladder leading up to it.
And then I got distracted by a wandering trader and quickly resumed my work and I used an
absurd amount of birch leaves to decorate.
If you can't tell from my pinterest page, birch leaves are my favorite.
Also if you're wondering how they move in the wind, that's the shaders and I use BSL
shaders.
As far as I know, they only work for Java Edition.
I made a little kitchen space in front of one of the windows complete with some cake
and some turtle eggs and then added some seating by the fire.
In front of the other window I made what HGTV calls a breakfast nook, complete with
some plants.
While the bedroom space is smaller than the previous build, I think it turned out nicely
and I wouldn't mind living there.
After decorating the bedroom, I remembered there was a bunch of empty space in the loft
which I promptly decorated with barrels because that can be practical when they're not converting
all the villagers to fishers, and I did notice I accidentally made a sort of shrine to Pinocchio
which is cool I guess.
On the outside I was going for a house-ish entrance, but I ended up making it more like
a hobbit hole with spruce trapdoors and slabs and stairs.
I also added some dark oak for better contrast and ended up expanding the windows downward
because it just looked better.
I added some shutters to the bedroom window and shroom lights to better illuminate it
at night.
There was something that was still missing though and I couldn't decide what to do so
I tried this thing I saw on TikTok where you make mushrooms out of end rods and mushroom
Mushroom Blocks, which I was a bit skeptical of, but I really liked how they turned out.
So yeah, those are three mushroom houses you could easily build in Minecraft.
Comment below which one you'd live in, I know I definitely would pick the second one because
of the skylight, but that's just me.
And if you enjoy this content and would like to see more dollar store green tutorials,
please feel free to hit subscribe.
See y'all later, byeeee!
you